<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ML for EDA on Patanjali SLPSK</title>
    <link>https://patanjali.github.io/tags/ml-for-eda/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ML for EDA on Patanjali SLPSK</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 06:41:32 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://patanjali.github.io/tags/ml-for-eda/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Karna: A Security Aware EDA Flow for Improved Side-Channel Attack Protection</title>
      <link>https://patanjali.github.io/publication/poster/paper5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 06:41:32 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patanjali.github.io/publication/poster/paper5/</guid>
      <description>Side-channel attacks pose a serious threat to the security of embedded devices. Most available countermeasures have significant overheads and very often do not meet an application’s requirement of low-power, high-performance, and small-area. In this work, we propose an algorithm called Karna that can be incorporated in the Electronic Design Automation (EDA) flow, in order to significantly improve the side-channel security of a device, without compromising on the other device characteristics of power, performance, and area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>White Mirror: Leaking Sensitive Information from Interactive Netflix Movies using Encrypted Traffic Analysis</title>
      <link>https://patanjali.github.io/publication/arxiv/paper4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 06:41:32 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patanjali.github.io/publication/arxiv/paper4/</guid>
      <description>Privacy leaks from Netflix videos/movies is well researched. Current state-of-the-art works have been able to obtain coarse-grained information such as the genre and the title of videos by passive observation of encrypted traffic. However, leakage of fine-grained information from encrypted traffic has not been studied so far. Such information can be used to build behavioural profiles of viewers. On 28th December 2018, Netflix released the first mainstream interactive movie called &amp;lsquo;Black Mirror: Bandersnatch&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MLTimer: Leakage Power Minimisation in Digital Circuits using Machine Learning and Adaptive Lazy Timing Analysis</title>
      <link>https://patanjali.github.io/publication/journal/paper1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2018 06:41:32 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patanjali.github.io/publication/journal/paper1/</guid>
      <description>Power optimization techniques in a VLSI flow typically end up being the performance bottlenecks leading to a large turn around time for the following reasons: * Scalability: The design typically spans millions and millions of gates with different operating conditions leading to a large search space. * Portability: The constraints vary across technology nodes hindering reusability of solutions. ML models are inherently trained to operate on large datasets and navigate a complex search space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GANDALF: A fine-grained hardware-software co-design for preventing memory attacks.</title>
      <link>https://patanjali.github.io/publication/journal/paper2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2018 06:41:32 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patanjali.github.io/publication/journal/paper2/</guid>
      <description>Illegal memory accesses are a serious security vulnerability that have been exploited on numerous occasions. In this letter, we present Gandalf, a compiler assisted hardware extension for the OpenRISC processor that thwarts all forms of memory-based attacks. We associate lightweight capabilities to all program variables, which are checked at run time by the hardware. Gandalf is transparent to the user and does not require significant OS modifications. Moreover, it achieves locality and incurs minimal overheads in the hardware.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HALTimer: A Fast Vt Replacement Heuristic for. Leakage Power Minimization </title>
      <link>https://patanjali.github.io/publication/poster/paper7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2015 06:41:32 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patanjali.github.io/publication/poster/paper7/</guid>
      <description>The discrete Vt sizing technique is employed at all stages of the physical synthesis flow, because it does not impact the placement yet provides significant room for power/timing optimization. The timing-constrained discrete Vt sizing problem (TC-DVSP) is NP-complete and earlier techniques reported for the same, employed iterative greedy or sensitivity-driven heuristics, that required incremental timing analysis after every iteration. The key observation reported in this paper is that there exists a good correlation between the slack distribution among gates in a given iteration and the order of gate replacements in subsequent iterations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FastReplace: Efficient Vt Replacement Technique for Leakage Power Minimization</title>
      <link>https://patanjali.github.io/publication/poster/paper6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2014 06:41:32 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patanjali.github.io/publication/poster/paper6/</guid>
      <description>We consider the timing-constrained discrete Vt-assignment problem for leakage minimization in digital circuits. The problem is known to be NP-complete. Greedy or Sensitivity-driven heuristics are known to be very effective for iterative Vt-assignment, with incremental timing analysis performed between the iterations. These heuristics, while offering good leakage power savings, carry a huge run-time penalty with increase in circuit size. In iterative Vt-assignment, we observe that there is a good correlation between the slack distribution in a given iteration, and the order of gate replacements in subsequent iterations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Implications of Shared Data Synchronization Techniques on Multi-Core Energy Efficiency.</title>
      <link>https://patanjali.github.io/publication/conference/paper3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2012 06:41:32 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://patanjali.github.io/publication/conference/paper3/</guid>
      <description>Shared data synchronization is at the heart of the multi-core revolution since it is essential for writing concurrent programs. Ideally, a synchronization technique should be able to fully exploit the available cores, leading to improved performance. However, with the growing demand for energy-efficient systems, it also needs to work within the energy and power budget of the system. In this paper, we perform a detailed study of the performance as well as energy efficiency of popular shared-data synchronization techniques on a commodity multi-core processor.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>